(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
さてと、今日は風真の1周年の配信だ
Alright, today is Kazama's 1st-anniversary stream.
そろそろ本番だし、パソコンの準備しようと
It's almost time, so I'll get the computer ready.
ちょうど1年前はデビュー前にパソコン壊しちゃったでござるからな
Exactly one year ago, I broke my computer right before my debut.
さすがに1年も経つわけだし、同じことが2度来るはずが...
Since a whole year has passed, there's no way the same thing would happen twice...
あ？
Huh?
あれ？
Oh?
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
つかないでござるな
It won't turn on.
こういう時は、叩けば直る！と！
In times like this, it'll be fixed if you hit it! Take that!
って、だめ？
Wait, no?
えい！よいしょ！
There! Hah!
ねえ！ちょっと！
Hey! Come on!
おい！
Hey!
おいおい！
Hey, hey!
あ〜 なんで？
Ah... why?
おかしいでござるな...
This is weird...
って、うわ！煙が出てる！
Wait, whoa! Smoke is coming out!
うわ、まずい、まずい、どうしよう！
Whoa, this is bad, bad, what should I do!
やばい！煙が！うわぁぁぁ！
Oh no! The smoke! Waaaah!
暫し待たれよ――
Please wait a moment――
2022年11月30日水曜日
Wednesday, November 30, 2022
20:00
holoXの用心棒、風真いろはの輝かしい1周年配信が始まる
The glorious 1st-anniversary stream of holoX's bodyguard, Kazama Iroha, begins.
はずだった
...Or so it was supposed to.
“1周年配信前にPCを破壊したって本当ですか？”
“Is it true that you destroyed your PC before the 1st-anniversary stream?”
壊しましたね...
I did break it...
また壊してしまったでござる
I broke it again.
「一周年配信前にPCを破壊したって本当ですか？」
"Is it true that you destroyed your PC before your 1st-anniversary stream?"
壊し... 壊してしまったでござる。
I... I ended up breaking it.
いやまさかね、また壊してしまうとは思ってもみなかったでござる。
I never would've thought that I'd break it again.
「なぜ壊れてしまったのですか？」
"Why did it break?"
正直、叩けば直ると思っていたでござるよ。
Honestly, I thought if I just hit it, it would start working.
まあ叩いて直るどころか、今度は爆発してしまったんでござるな。
Well, instead of fixing it, it ended up exploding this time.
「１周年配信を迎えている未来の自分に一言ありますか？」
"Do you have a message for your future self who is celebrating the 1st-anniversary stream?"
いやまた逃げられないでござるよ、風真。
No, you can't run away again, Kazama.
こうなったら腹くくって皆殿の前に出て...
Now that it's come to this, brace yourself and go before everyone...
誠心誠意、謝罪とその心を皆殿に見せるでござる。
and show your sincere apology and feelings to everyone.
あ、あー。えー、皆様。
Ah, ah. Um, everyone.
この度は一周年配信の前に、
Before this 1st-anniversary stream,
パソコン殿直るかなーって叩いたあげく、
I hit my PC thinking it might fix it,
壊してしまい皆殿にご心配、
but ended up breaking it and worrying everyone,
そして運営様に多大なるご迷惑をおかけしまして、
and causing a lot of trouble for the staff.
本当に申し訳ございませんでした。あああああ！
I am truly, very sorry. AAAAAAAH!
しかし！一年前の風真とは違う！
However! I'm not the same Kazama as I was a year ago!
この一年で風真は成長しました！
I have grown over this past year!
自分のパソコンぐらい、アイドルパワーで直してやるでござる！
I'll fix my own PC with idol power!
歌って踊って、成長した姿を見せるでござるよ！
I'll sing and dance to show you how much I've grown!
いざ、ライブ会場へ！
Now, to the live venue!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
うおー！いくぞいくぞいくぞー！
Whoa! Let's go, let's go, let's go!
うおー！きたきたきたきたー！到着！
Whoa! Here I am, here I am! I've arrived!
皆殿、こんばんわでござる！
Good evening, everyone!
ホロライブ6期生、秘密結社holoXの用心棒、
Hololive 6th gen, the bodyguard of Secret Society holoX,
侍の風真いろはでござる！
the samurai Kazama Iroha!
ヤッホー！お待たせしました！
Yoo-hoo! Sorry to keep you waiting!
今日は風真いろは一周年ライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to Kazama Iroha's 1st-anniversary live today!
そして直前でパソコンのみならず、あの枠も破壊してしまいまして、
And just before this, I destroyed not only my PC but also the stream link,
本当に申し訳ございませんでした！
so I am truly sorry!
もうどんだけ物壊すねんて、めっちゃ皆殿思ってるかもしれないんですけど、
You might be thinking, "how much stuff is she going to break?"
いろいろありましたが、無事に一周年配信をスタートすることができました！
A lot happened, but I've successfully started the 1st-anniversary stream!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
#風真いろは一周年ライブ でたくさん呟いて、
Please tweet a lot with #KazamaIroha1stAnniversaryLive,
スクショとかもいっぱいバシバシしてくれたら嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
and I'd be happy if you take lots of screenshots! Please and thank you!
はい、ね。今日はここでたくさん歌って踊って、アイドルパワーを貯めるでござる！
Yes. Today, I'll sing and dance a lot here to gather idol power!
あ、そう、アイドルパワーが何かね、と説明しない、でござるな。
Oh, right, I haven't explained what idol power is yet.
それでは、説明しよう！
Now then, allow me to explain!
「アイドルメーター」
Idol Meter
皆様！こちらです！
Everyone! It's this!
ああー。まだ0のままでござるか。
Ah. It's still at 0.
あ、そう。このパワーは風真がアイドルっぽいことをすればメーターが溜まって、
Yes, this power gauge fills up when I do idol-like things.
そんで、このパワーがマックスになったら、
And when this power reaches its maximum,
この一周年のために頑張って準備してた、あれとかそれとかこれとか、
the things I've worked hard to prepare for this 1st anniversary,
いっぱいこのデータが詰まったあのパソコンを、復活させることができるという考えでござる！
that PC filled with all that data can be revived! That's the idea!
きっと直る！
It will definitely be fixed!
ってかパソコンが直らないと、せっかく皆殿のために準備したあれが、
I mean, if the PC doesn't get fixed, that thing I prepared for everyone,
そう、あれが発表できないでござる！ヤバい！
yes, that can't be announced! This is bad!
どうしよう。ま、でもね、やるしかない！
What should I do? Well, there's nothing for it but to do it!
ということで、早速、アイドルパワーを貯めていくぞー！
So, without further ado, let's start gathering idol power!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
それでは皆殿聞いてください！1曲目。
Now then, everyone, please listen! The first song.
風真の中でアイドルといえばこれ！
When I think of idols, this is the one!
行きます！『ハートはお手上げ』。
Here we go! "Heart wa Oteage".
大好き君のシルエット
I love your silhouette
キラキラきらめいて
Sparkling and glittering
走り出した 気持ちは今
The feelings that started running now
境界線を 飛び越えるよ
Will jump over the boundary line
ハート捕まえて
Catch my heart
踏み出した雨の中
Stepping out into the rain
歩幅を合わせて歩いた
We walked in step with each other
傘を叩く雨粒の音
The sound of raindrops hitting the umbrella
私の鼓動もよう
Like the rhythm of my heartbeat
信号赤のまま
While the signal is still red
ああ 時間よ止まって
Ah, please let time stop
苦しいくらい想いが 溢れてく
Emotions are overflowing so much it hurts
YES 君のシルエット
YES, your silhouette
ゆらゆらり揺らめいて
Swaying and shimmering
動き出した世界の中
In the world that started moving
瞳はスローモーション
My eyes are in slow motion
言葉にできない
I can't put it into words
不器用な君のこと
About you who are clumsy
全部ギュッと抱きしめたら
If I hug you tight
境界線も飛び越えるよ
I'll jump over the boundary line
もう止まらない
I can't stop anymore
ハートはお手上げ
Hearts are up
真夜中にスマホが鳴り
My smartphone rings in the middle of the night
君の名前が光って
Your name lights up
嬉しいのに切なくなる
I'm happy but it makes me feel bittersweet
終わらない迷路みたい
Like an endless maze
優しくしないで
Don't be kind to me
戻れなくなるから
Because I won't be able to go back
寄せては返す想いが
Emotions that come and go
ざわめいて
Are buzzing
YES 恋のファンファーレ
YES, the fanfare of love
どこまでも鳴り響け
Resound everywhere
色付いてく気持ちは今
Feelings that are getting colored now
誰にも止められない
Nobody can stop them
素直になれない
I can't be honest
あまのじゃくな私は
With my perverse self
全部ギュッと抱きしめてね
Hold me tight completely
せーので未来へ飛び込むから
Because we'll jump into the future together
覚悟してね
Be prepared
ハートを捕まえて
Catch my heart
気が付けば
When I realized
夢の中
I was in a dream
出口 YES NO YES NO
Exit, YES NO YES NO
風が 吹いたの
The wind blew
君のそば 祈りな
By your side, I pray
恋してる
I'm in love
君のシルエット
Your silhouette
ゆらゆらり揺らめいて
Swaying and shimmering
動き出した世界の中
In the world that started moving
瞳はスローモーション
My eyes are in slow motion
言葉にできない
I can't put it into words
不器用な君のこと
About you who are clumsy
全部ギュッと抱きしめたら
If I hug you tight
境界線も飛び越えるよ
I'll jump over the boundary line
もう止まらない
I can't stop anymore
ハートはお手上げ
Hearts are up
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、一曲目は風真の大好きな
And so, the first song was one of Kazama's favorites,
鈴木愛理さんの「ハートはお手上げ」でしたー！
Suzuki Airi-san's "Heart wa Oteage"!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
コメント見えてるぞ。
I can see your comments.
「この可愛さにはお手上げ」
"Giving up on this cuteness."
それは、本当でござるか？
Is that really true?
やった！頑張った甲斐があった！
Yay! It was worth the effort!
「あ、めっちゃ可愛い」って言ってくれてる！
"Ah, so cute," you're saying!
皆殿、ありがとう！頑張ったよ！
Everyone, thank you! I worked hard!
もう、本当にね、風真の中でアイドルの
Seriously, she's someone I look up to
お手本にしている方なので、
as an idol role model,
一周年でね、大好きなその方の、
so for my 1st anniversary,
鈴木愛理さんの「ハートはお手上げ」やらせていただきました！
I performed Suzuki Airi-san's "Heart wa Oteage"!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
「アイドルっぽかった？」
"Did I look like an idol?"
「あ、アイドルっぽかった？」
"Ah, did I look like an idol?"
良かったかな？
Was it good?
おっ！ということは、これでアイドルパワー
Oh! That means my idol power
上がってるはず！
should be up!
どうだ？どうですか？
How is it? How do you think?
アイドルメーター
Idol Meter
上がってる！やった！上がってるよ、皆殿！
It's up! Yay! It's up, everyone!
やったー！
Hooray!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
この調子でね、ガンガン頑張っていきますので、
I'll keep going strong like this,
そしてそしてね、ゲストの方も駆けつけてくれているので
and also, a guest has come to join us,
お楽しみに！
so look forward to it!
あ！昨日追加したパワー注入もいっぱい使ってくれてありがとう！
Ah! Thanks for using the Power Injection I added yesterday!
よし！
Alright!
それでは次の曲、行きますよ！
Then, let's go to the next song!
レッツゴー！！
Let's go!!
会いたくて 恋しくて 離れて
I want to see you, I miss you, being apart
あの日はもう来ない
That day will never come again
桜ロック / 作詞・作曲：MEEKO
Sakura Rock / Lyrics & Composition: MEEKO
等身大の自分 遠くの君に
My life-sized self, to you far away
手を振るよ Put your hands up! Yeah! Boy!
I wave my hand, Put your hands up! Yeah! Boy!
淡い香りが漂う 季節が巡りくる
A faint scent drifts, the season comes around
心はずませていた頃
When my heart was racing
今よみがえるよ
It all comes back to me now
初めて恋をしたんだ
I fell in love for the first time
何もかも輝いていた
Everything was shining
少しの時間でさえも
Even just a little bit of time
一緒に時を刻んでいた
We spent it together
サクラ咲いた 木の下で君の声を
Under the blooming cherry blossoms, your voice...
春風が邪魔して聞こえない
...is drowned out by the spring breeze
サヨナラじゃないと願った
I prayed it wasn't a goodbye
逢いたくて 恋しくて 離れて
I miss you, I love you, and now we're apart
あの日の笑顔が 舞い散って
The smile from that day flutters away
いつでも もっと近かった
We were always so much closer
君はもういない
But you're no longer here
叶うなら サクラが舞い降りる
If it could come true, let the cherry blossoms fall
来年も今も
Next year, and even now
肩並べ 写真でも撮りたいな
I want to stand by your side and take a photo
あの日はもう来ない
That day will never come again
会いたいな 手のひらほら花びら
I want to see you, look, petals in my palm
空に光る星が傷口をつつくんだ
The stars shining in the sky prick at my wounds
もう恋なんてしないよ
I'll never fall in love again
君に一番言いたかった
That's what I wanted to tell you most of all
雨が降って 二人で入った傘も
Even the umbrella we shared when it rained
待ち合わせしたあの駅も
And that station where we used to meet
もう一人じゃ行きたくないよ
I don't want to go there alone anymore
好きだった 小生意気な手紙は
I loved them, those cheeky letters...
今さらいらない
...I don't need them now
別れ際 優しくするなら
If you're going to be kind as we part
そばにいてほしい
Then I want you by my side
あの日を待ってる 一人ぼっちの僕を
Waiting for that day, all by myself
思い出のあの曲を 小さい声で歌う
I sing that song of memories in a small voice
もう恋なんてしないよ なんて ただの嘘で
'I'll never fall in love again' was just a lie
もう忘れられないなんて ただの冗談で
'I can't forget you' was just a joke
忘れたくなくて 結局
In the end, I didn't want to forget
君に恋していたいよ
I want to stay in love with you
逢いたくて 恋しくて 離れて
I miss you, I love you, and now we're apart
あの日の笑顔が 舞い散って
The smile from that day flutters away
いつでも もっと近かった
We were always so much closer
君はもういない
But you're no longer here
ラジオからあの曲 二人でいた部屋で
That song on the radio, in the room we shared
自然と涙があふれ出る
Tears just start flowing naturally
別れ際の笑顔が 一番 眩しく見えた
Your smile as we parted looked the brightest of all
咲かせよう サクラが舞い降りて
Let's make them bloom, the cherry blossoms falling
弱い自分から 抜け出せる
I can break free from my weak self
涙も音奏で 旋律を歌う
My tears make music as I sing the melody
ラジオから春の歌
A song of spring from the radio
もうそんな季節で
It's already that time of year
サヨナラをグッと飲み込んだ
I swallowed back my goodbye
思い出の1ページ 鮮やかに残る
A page of memories remains vividly
アズアズ！ 一緒に歌ってくれて ありがとうでござる！
AZ-AZ! Thank you for singing with me!
こちらこそ 誘ってくれてありがとう いろはちゃん！ やったー！
Likewise, thank you for inviting me, Iroha-chan! We did it!
この『桜ロック』は アズアズの声にぴったりだなって思って 選曲しました！
I chose 'Sakura Rock' because I thought it would suit your voice perfectly, AZ-AZ!
そうなんだ！ 今回はね いろはちゃんに選曲してもらって 初めてこの曲歌いました！
I see! This was actually my first time singing this song, thanks to your choice, Iroha-chan!
嬉しい！ 二人でハモったり そしてユニゾンしたり ラップもしちゃったりして 可愛い振り付けだったでしょう？ 楽しかったです！
I'm so happy! We harmonized, sang in unison, and even did some rap. The choreography was cute, right? It was so much fun!
いろはちゃん 本当に1周年おめでとう！
Iroha-chan, happy 1st anniversary!
ありがとうでござる！ アズアズとは『Android Girl』の歌ってみたとか... コラボぶりでござるな！ また一緒に歌えて嬉しいし 今日はステージの上でやった！
Thank you! It's been a while since our 'Android Girl' cover collaboration! I'm so happy we could sing together again, and this time on stage!
このステージ来たかった！ やったー！ やったー！
I've always wanted to come to this stage! We did it! Yay!
アイドルっぽさ全開だったでござるな！
It felt totally like an idol performance!
わ！ ということは？ これでまたアイドルパワーが貯まったはずでござる！
Whoa! That means... our idol power must have increased again!
おー、溜まった！
Oh, it's full!
こ、ここぞ！
T-this is it!
お、おお、おお！
Oh, oh, oh!
おー、溜まってる！
Oh, it's full!
やったー！
We did it!
ござ、ござ！
Goza, goza!
やったー、よかった、よかった。
We did it! I'm so glad, I'm so glad.
やったー、あずちゃん！
We did it, AZ-chan!
ありがとうございます、でござる。
Thank you very much, de-gozaru.
また絶対二人で一緒に歌おうね。
Let's definitely sing together again.
もちろんでござる！
Of course, de-gozaru!
それでは、一人目のゲストは、あずあずでした！
And so, our first guest was AZ-AZ!
あずきでしたー！ありがとー！
It was AZKi! Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
カルマ
作詞・作曲：藤原基央
Karma
Lyrics & Composition: Motoo Fujiwara
ガラス玉ひとつ落とされた
A single glass bead was dropped
追いかけてもひとつ落っこちた
Even if I chased it, another one fell
ひとつ分の陽だまりに　ひとつだけ残ってる
In a single spot of sunlight, only one remains
心臓が始まった時　嫌でも人は場所を取る
When the heart started beating, people took up space whether they liked it or not
奪われない様に守り続けてる
Continuing to protect it so it won't be stolen
汚さずに保ってきた　手でも汚れて見えた
I kept it clean, but even so it looked dirty in my hands
記憶を疑う前に　記憶に疑われている
Before doubting my memories, I am being doubted by them
必ず僕らは出会うだろう
We will surely meet
同じ鼓動の音を目印にして
Using the sound of the same heartbeat as a sign
ここにいるよ
I'm here
いつだって呼んでるから
Because I'm always calling
くたびれた理由が重なって揺れる時
When tired reasons overlap and sway
生まれた意味を知る
I learn the meaning of being born
存在が続く限り　仕方ないから場所を取る
As long as existence continues, I take up space because I have no choice
ひとつ分の陽だまりに　ふたつはちょっと入れない
In a single spot of sunlight, two can't quite fit
ガラス玉ひとつ落とされた　落ちた時何か弾き出した
A single glass bead was dropped; it kicked something out when it fell
奪い取った場所で光を浴びた
In the place I snatched away, I was bathed in light
数えた足跡など　気付けば数字でしかない
The footprints I counted, before I knew it, were nothing but numbers
知らなきゃいけない事は　どうやら1と0の間
What I need to know seems to be between 1 and 0
初めて僕らは出会うだろう
We will meet for the first time
同じ悲鳴の旗を目印にして
Using the flag of the same scream as a sign
忘れないで
Don't forget
いつだって呼んでるから
Because I'm always calling
重なった理由も二人で埋める時
When we bury the overlapping reasons together
約束が交わされる
A promise is exchanged
鏡なんだ　僕ら互いに
We are mirrors of each other
それぞれのカルマを映す為の
To reflect our respective karmas
汚れた手と手で触り合って
Touching each other with dirty hands
形がわかる
We understand the shape
ここにいるよ
I'm here
確かに触れるよ
I can certainly be touched
ひとり分の陽だまりに　僕らはいる
In a single spot of sunlight, we are here
忘れないで
Don't forget
いつだって呼んでるから
Because I'm always calling
同じガラス玉の内側の方から
From the inside of the same glass bead
そうさ必ず僕らは出会うだろう
That's right, we will surely meet
沈めた理由に十字架を立てる時
When we set a cross on the submerged reasons
約束は果たされる
The promise is fulfilled
僕らはひとつになる
We become one
はっ！
Ha!
打上花火
作詞・作曲：米津玄師
Uchiage Hanabi
Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
あの日見渡した渚を　今も思い出すんだ
I still remember the shore we looked out over that day
砂の上に刻んだ言葉　君の後ろ姿
Words carved on the sand, the sight of your back
寄り返す波が　足元をよぎり何かをさらう
The returning waves pass by my feet and snatch something away
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見てた
I was watching the fireworks that flashed and bloomed
きっとまだ 終わらない夏が
Surely the summer that's not over yet...
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
Melts and connects my ambiguous heart
この夜が 続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to continue
あと何回君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I can see the same fireworks with you
笑い顔に何ができるだろうか
I wonder what I can do for your smiling face
傷つくこと 喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と情動
Hurting, rejoicing, waves and emotions that repeat
焦燥 最終列車の音
Frustration, the sound of the last train
何度でも言葉にして君を呼ぶよ 波を選び
No matter how many times, I'll put it into words and call you, choosing the waves
もう一度
One more time
もう二度と 悲しい夏に
Never again, in a sad summer...
戻らぬように
So that we never return
パッと息を呑めば 消えちゃいそうな光が
When I catch my breath, the light that seems about to disappear...
きっとまだ 胸に住んでいた
Was surely still living in my heart
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は
The warm future that I touched when I reached out
密かに二人を見ていた
Was secretly watching the two of us
パッと花火が
The fireworks suddenly...
夜に咲いた
Bloomed in the night
夜に咲いて
Blooming in the night
静かに消えた
And quietly disappeared
離さないで
Don't let go
もう少しだけ
Just a little longer
このままで
Stay like this
あの日見渡した渚を
The shore we looked out over that day...
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it even now
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words carved in the sand
君の後ろ姿
The view of your back
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見てた
I was watching the fireworks that flashed and bloomed
きっとまだ 終わらない夏が
Surely the summer that's not over yet...
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
Melts and connects my ambiguous heart
この夜が 続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to continue
というわけで！
And so!
2人目のゲストは かなた先輩でござるー！
The second guest is Kanata-senpai!
はいはーい！
Hi hi!
いろはちゃん、1周年おめでとう！
Iroha-chan, happy 1st anniversary!
ありがとうでござる！
Thank you very much!
呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thanks for inviting me!
一緒にMIX企画とかやったし、いつか一緒に歌いたいなって思ってました！
We did a mix project together and I've been wanting to sing with you someday!
願い叶って嬉しいでござる！
I'm so happy my wish came true!
いや、僕もね、一緒に歌いたいと思っていましたし...
Well, I also wanted to sing with you...
今回、あの選んでくれた「打上花火」は、男の人と女の人のデュエットの曲なので...
The 'Uchiage Hanabi' you chose this time is a duet for a man and a woman...
ちょっとね、僕たちカップルみたいじゃない？
So, don't we look a bit like a couple?
あれ、カップルかな？2人でデートもしたし。
Wait, maybe a couple? We even went on a date together.
恥ずかしいけど、嬉しいでござる！
It's embarrassing, but I'm happy!
また一緒にお出かけしたいでござる！
I want to go out with you again!
しようね、しようね。しましょうね！
Let's do that, let's do that. Let's!
そしてそして、見てください！
And and, please look!
お揃いの浴衣でござる！
Matching yukatas!
どうですか？見て見て。
What do you think? Take a look.
可愛いでござる！
It's cute!
可愛いでしょ？見て見て。
It's cute, right? Take a look.
これも完全に、お揃いでね。
These are also completely matching.
お揃いにしてもらったでござる！
We had them made to match!
きていただきました！ねー！
Thank you for coming! Right?
ねー！
Right!
そうだ！浴衣効果で
Oh, right! Maybe the yukata effect
いろはのアイドルパワーが貯まったのではないでござるか！？
filled up Iroha's Idol Power!?
アイドルパワー？
Idol Power?
アイドルメーター
Idol Meter
なんか出てきたな
Something came out.
おっ？なんか…なんだろうこれ
Oh? Some... what is this?
おおー！貯まった貯まった！
Ooh! It's filling up, it's filling up!
よくわからんけど、やったー！
I don't really get it, but yay!
可愛い可愛い！
Cute, cute!
ありがとでござるー
Thank you degozaru~
ありがとねー
Thank you~
また一緒に歌いましょうね！
Let's sing together again!
本当だね！絶対歌おう！
True! Let's definitely sing!
ありがとう
Thank you
ありがとうございましたー
Thank you very much~
じゃあねーバイバーイ！
Bye bye!
次は、お泊り行こうね！
Next, let's have a sleepover!
ああー！ぜひ行きましょう！
Ah! Let's definitely go!
またねー！
See you!
小さきもの
Chiisaki Mono (Small One)
静かにただ見つめてた
I was just quietly gazing
小さきもの　眠る顔
At the sleeping face of a small one
眉間にしわ少しだけ寄せてる
With a slight frown between their eyebrows
恐い夢なら　目を覚まして
If it's a scary dream, please wake up
自らが怖くてしり込みしてた
I was afraid of myself and hesitated
あの夏がよみがえる
That summer comes back to me
背中押されてはやっと泳げた
Pushed from behind, I could finally swim
まるで奇跡みたいです
It's almost like a miracle
声が聞こえる
I can hear a voice
行くべき道を指し示している
Pointing the way I should go
さらさら流れる風の中で一人
Alone in the rustling wind
私歌っています
I am singing
小さきもの　それは私
The small one is me
私です　まぎれなく
It is me, without a doubt
鏡の中心細さだけが
Inside the mirror, only my insecurity...
誰にも負けない明日になるよ
...will become a tomorrow that yields to no one
そして私は幼い頃に
And I, towards my childhood...
少しずつ戻ってゆく
...am gradually returning
意味も知らず歌う恋の歌を
Singing a love song without knowing its meaning
褒めてくれたあの日々に
To those days when you praised me
空を仰げば
When I look up at the sky
満ちてくる私の声が
My voice wells up and fills me
さらさら流れる風の中で君も
You too, in the rustling wind...
ふわり舞い上がれ
...soar up softly
声が聞こえる
I can hear a voice
行くべき道を指し示している
Pointing the way I should go
さらさら流れる風の中で一人
Alone in the rustling wind
私歌っています
I am singing
大切なものはすぐそばにある
The things that matter are right by my side...
そのことに気づいた
...I realized that.
空を仰げば 満ちてくる
When I look up at the sky, it fills up
私の声が サラサラ流る
My voice flows smoothly
風の中で
In the wind
君もふんわり舞い上がれ
You too, gently soar up
声が聞こえる 行く先未知
I can hear a voice, destination unknown
指さしている
It is pointing the way
サラサラ流る 風の中で
Flowing smoothly in the wind
一人私 歌っているわ
Alone, I am singing
はい、というわけで、小さきもの、歌わせていただきましたー！
Alright, and so, I sang "Chiisaki Mono"!
どうだったでござるか？
How was it?
ね、今ポケモンをね、めちゃめちゃこの風真もやっているので、
Since I've been playing a lot of Pokemon lately,
風真の大好きなポケモンジラーチの映画のね、主題歌を歌わせていただきました！
I sang the theme song from the Jirachi movie, which is one of my favorites!
めっちゃ拍手ありがとう！
Thank you so much for the applause!
も、めっちゃ皆殿がパワー注入してくれてるの見てたよ、ありがとう！
I saw everyone sending me power, thank you!
そして、今回なんと！初公開、こちらのステージ、秋になりましたー！
And now! For the first time, this stage has turned into autumn!
見てめっちゃ綺麗！すごい、すごいくないでござるか？
Look, it's so beautiful! Amazing, isn't it?
めっちゃ綺麗！すごい！
It's so pretty! Wow!
今ね、初めからスタートして春夏秋までやってきましたが、いかがでしょうか？
We've gone through spring and summer, and now we're in autumn. What do you think?
このね、紅葉のね、綺麗綺麗パワーとね、ジラーチの力を借りて、きっとアイドルパワー溜まったんじゃないかな？
With the beautiful power of the autumn leaves and Jirachi's help, I'm sure my idol power has charged up!
どうだ？アイドルパワーは？
How's it looking? My idol power?
お、上がってる！お、やったぜ皆殿！ほら見てめちゃくちゃ上がってる！
Oh, it's going up! Yes, everyone! Look, it's rising like crazy!
お、お、どんどん上がっちゃう！すごい！めっちゃ上がってるよ！
Oh, oh, it keeps going up! Incredible! It's rising so much!
皆殿のこの注入のおかげ！え、ちょっとみんな注入して？注入して？
It's all thanks to your power! Hey, everyone, keep sending it! Keep sending it!
え、ちょっと待って今下がったんだけど。え、どうしたの？
Wait a minute, it just went down. What happened?
ちょ、下げないで！ちょ、皆殿がいっぱい注入してるから！ちょっと、やめて下げないで、ちょっと！
Hey, don't let it drop! Everyone's sending so much! Stop, don't let it go down!
注入、注入、注入！
Send it, send it, send it!
あーちょっと何で下がるの？何で？何で何で何で何で何で！
Ah, wait, why is it dropping? Why? Why why why why why!
あ、そうそうそう！注入、注入、注入！お、お、来た？
Ah, that's it! Send it, send it, send it! Oh, is it coming?
あ、やったー！上がった！上がったー！
Ah, hooray! It went up! It went up!
いや皆殿協力ありがとう！あぶねー、風真一人だったら下がるところだったでござるよ！
Everyone, thank you for your help! That was close, it would've dropped if I was alone!
やった、え？何か今速報が...
Yes! Eh? I'm getting some breaking news...
あ、何かTwitterのハッシュタグがトレンド1位みたい！
Oh, it looks like our Twitter hashtag is trending #1!
やったー！皆殿のおかげだ！めっちゃパワー注入してくれたおかげでござる！ありがとうございます！
Hooray! It's all thanks to you! Thanks for sending so much power! Thank you very much!
たくさんスクショも撮ってくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you for taking so many screenshots too!
このままね、あのアイドルパワーマックスまで突っ走っていきたいと思いますので！
I want to keep charging ahead until my idol power is maxed out!
皆殿最後まで応援してください！って言っても...
So everyone, please support me until the end! Having said that...
あとこのちょっとの壁が大きいんでござるよな...
This last little bit is a big hurdle...
まあ我々HoloX、一周年記念配信リレー最後ということで、風真がやっておりますが...
Well, since this is the finale of our HoloX 1st Anniversary relay stream, I'm the one performing, but...
やっぱりアイドルになった我々の力ということで、最後は...
Ultimately, it's about our collective power as idols, so for the finale...
あいつらを呼ぶか！
Let's call them out!
キセキ
作詞・作曲：GReeeeN
Kiseki
Lyrics & Composition: GReeeeN
明日 今日よりも好きになれる
Tomorrow, I will be able to love you more than today
溢れる想いが止まらない
My overflowing feelings won't stop
今もこんなに好きでいるのに
Even though I love you this much right now
言葉に出来ない
I can't put it into words
君のくれた日々が積み重なり
The days you gave me pile up
過ぎ去った日々 2人歩いた「軌跡」
The days gone by, the "path" we walked together
僕らの出会いがもし偶然ならば
If our meeting was just a coincidence
運命ならば 君に...
If it was destiny, then to you...
巡り会えた　それって奇跡
Meeting you, that's a miracle
誰よりそばにいて歩いて　永遠の愛を形にして
Walking by your side more than anyone,
shaping eternal love
いつまでも君の横で　笑っていたくて
I want to keep smiling by your side forever
ありがとうや　ああ　愛してるじゃ
Saying "Thank you" or "I love you"...
まだ足りないけど　せめて言わせて　「幸せです」と
...isn't enough, but let me at least say,
"I'm happy"
いつも君の右の手のひらを
Always, your right palm...
ただ僕の左の手のひらが
...is simply held by my left palm
そっと包んでく　それだけで
Gently wrapping around it, just with that...
ただ愛を感じていた
...I was just feeling love
日々の中で　小さな幸せ
In our daily lives, small moments of happiness...
見つけ重ね　ゆっくり歩いた軌跡
Found and gathered, the tracks of our slow walk
僕らの出会いは大きな世界で
Our meeting, in this big world...
小さな出来事　巡り会えた　それって奇跡
...is a small event, but meeting you,
that's a miracle
うまくいかない日だって　二人でいれば晴れだって
Even on days when things don't go well,
as long as we're together, it's sunny
強がりや寂しさも　忘れられるから
Because I can forget my bluffing and loneliness
僕は君でなら
If it's because of you...
僕でいれるから　だからいつもそばにいてよ
...I can be myself, so always stay by my side
愛しい君へ　例えばずっと
To my dear you, for example, always...
明日今日より笑顔になれる
Tomorrow, I can smile more than today
君がいるだけで　そう思えるから
Just because you're here, I can think that
何十年　何百年　何千年
Decades, centuries, millennia...
時を超えよう　君を愛してる
...let's transcend time, I love you
例えばほら　明日を見失いそうに
For example, look, if we're about to lose sight
of tomorrow...
僕らなったとしても
...even if we become like that
誰よりそばにいて歩いて　永遠の愛を形にして
Walking by your side more than anyone,
shaping eternal love
いつまでも君の横で　笑っていたくて
I want to keep smiling by your side forever
ありがとうや　ああ　愛してるじゃ
Saying "Thank you" or "I love you"...
まだ足りないけど　せめて言わせて　「幸せです」と
...isn't enough, but let me at least say,
"I'm happy"
うまくいかない日だって　二人でいれば晴れだって
Even on days when things don't go well,
as long as we're together, it's sunny
喜びや悲しみも　全て分け合える
All the joys and sorrows, we can share them all
君がいるから　生きていけるから
Because you're here, because I can keep living
だからいつもそばにいてよ　愛しい君へ
So always stay by my side, to my dear you
最後の一秒まで
Until the very last second
明日今日より笑顔になれる
Tomorrow, I can smile more than today
君がいるだけで　そう思えるから
Just because you're here, I can think that
何十年　何百年　何千年　時を超えよう
Decades, centuries, millennia, let's transcend time
君を愛してる
I love you
holoX 大集合でござる！
holoX is all gathered here!
（歓声）
(Cheers)
というわけで、holoX で GReeeeN さんの「キセキ」を歌わせていただきました！
And so, holoX performed GReeeeN-san's
"Kiseki"!
みんな今日は来てくれてありがとうでござる！
Everyone, thank you for coming today!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
実はデビューしてからずっと夢だったことがあって、風真のチャンネルに holoX が集合したことなかったから、
Actually, there's something that's been my dream
ever since debut: holoX had never all gathered
on Kazama's channel before...
1周年までにみんなに来てほしいなって思っていたら、あっという間に1年経ってました。
I was hoping everyone could come by the 1st
anniversary, and a year passed in the blink of
an eye.
わかる！ 早い！
I know! It's so fast!
凸待ちとかで来てくれたことはあったけど、自分からみんなを呼べて、本当に嬉しいでござる。ありがとう！
You've come for call-ins and such, but being
able to invite everyone myself makes me
really happy. Thank you!
呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting us!
よし！ みんなのおかげでアイドルゲージがたくさん増えたのでは？！
Alright! Thanks to everyone, the Idol Gauge
has increased a lot, hasn't it?!
上がる上がる！
It's going up, it's going up!
みんなのおかげで全部たまったでござる！ ありがとう！
Thanks to everyone, it's all full! Thank you!
やったー！ おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
よし、これでパソコンが直りそうなので、ラストスパート頑張るでござる！
Alright, it looks like the PC will be fixed now,
so I'll do my best for the final stretch!
それじゃあみんな、またアジトで会おうぜ！
Well then everyone, see you back at the hideout!
オッケー！ 帰りましょう！
Okay! Let's go home!
ありがとー！ばいばーい！頑張ってねー！頑張ってにぇ！
Thank you! Bye-bye! Good luck! Do your best!
現場のぽこべーさーん！
Pokobe-san on the scene!
先程アイドルパワーがマックスになったでござるが
My idol power just hit max, but...
パソコンさんの調子はいかがでござるか？
...how's the PC doing?
あー、まだ直ってないでござるな。煙吹いてるし
Ah, it's not fixed yet. It's smoking...
火花もバチバチだー。おかしいな...
...and there are sparks everywhere. That's weird...
確かにさっきパワーマックスになったはずなのに
I'm sure my power hit max earlier.
あー！ごめん！ぽこべー！ぽこべー！
Ah! Sorry! Pokobe! Pokobe!
持ちこたえて！ごめんね！お？何かひらめいたか？
Hang in there! Sorry! Oh? Did you think of something?
どうした？どうした？なんだ？おもむろに何を取り出すんだ？
What's up? What's wrong? What are you taking out all of a sudden?
待ってるぞ、風真は。大丈夫か？怪我、怪我しないでほしいでござるよ。
I'm waiting. You okay? I hope you don't get hurt.
ちょっと待て！まさか、おまえそれはまずい！
Wait a minute! No way, that's bad!
それはまずい！叩いて直らないことはこの1年で学んだって！
That's bad! We learned this year that hitting it doesn't fix it!
やめとけ！あー！やばい！壊れる！壊れる！
Stop it! Ah! No! It'll break! It'll break!
壊れる！やめて！あ、あ、ついた！？
It'll break! Stop! Ah, ah, it turned on!?
うそでしょ？ついたんだけど！え！？
No way? It actually turned on! Huh!?
ぽこべーすごい！ぽこべーすごいよ！
Pokobe, you're amazing! You're amazing, Pokobe!
ありがとう、ぽこべー！ついたー！やったー！直ったー！
Thank you, Pokobe! It's on! Yay! It's fixed!
というわけで皆殿、
So, everyone,
パソコンさんが無事バッチリ直りましたー！
the PC is now perfectly fixed!
これでやっと1周年のために準備した
All the data I prepared
あれやこれや重大なデータが復活しました！
for the 1st anniversary is finally back!
よし、ここからがね、ラストスパート！
Alright, time for the final stretch!
皆殿、ちゃんと最後まで見てててくださいねー！
Everyone, please watch until the very end!
Color of Drops
作詞・作曲: 40mP
Lyrics & Composition: 40mP
誰かに与えられた色を纏って
Wearing a color someone else gave me
違う誰かを演じてきた
I played the role of someone else
胸に手を当てて歌うこれが
Singing with my hand on my heart,
私だって言い聞かせるように
Trying to convince myself "this is me"
憧れにはほど遠く 落ち込むばかりの毎日で
Far from my ideals, every day was just full of feeling down
閉ざされた瞳から 雫がこぼれ落ちてゆく
From my closed eyes, a drop spills and falls away
何千回私が生まれ変わったとしても
Even if I were to be reborn thousands of times
きっともう二度と私にはなれやしないから
I'm sure I could never become "me" ever again
本当の私を偽りのないこの色を
My true self, this color without any lies
歌声に乗せてモノクロの世界を彩るよ
I'll put them in my song and color this monochrome world
誰かに望まれた色を探し
I've walked along looking for
見つけるために歩いてきた
A color someone else wanted from me
気づけば現在地も思いも見失って迷子になっていた
Before I knew it, I'd lost my place and my thoughts, and I was lost
無理矢理笑顔作って自分を騙すことばかり
Just forcing smiles and deceiving myself
青く澄んだ空から雫がこぼれ落ちてきた
From the clear blue sky, a drop came falling down
何千回私が光を浴びたとしても
Even if I were bathed in light thousands of times
嘘を重ねた色じゃ輝けないから
I can't shine with a color made of layered lies
本当の私を偽りのないこの色を
My true self, this color without any lies
強く抱きしめて茜色の虹を架けに行くよ
I'll hold them tight and go to build a madder-red rainbow
不器用で
Clumsy and
強がりで
stubborn,
泣き虫で
a crybaby,
頼りなくて
unreliable...
でも それも これも 全部
But even so, I'll take all of that
受け止めていくんだ
and embrace it all.
何千回 私が生まれ変わったとしても
Even if I were to be reborn thousands of times,
きっともっと私には なれやしないから
I surely wouldn't be able to become "me" any better than this.
本当の私が 偽りのない この色が
The real me, this color without any lies,
誰かの心に届く日を信じて (Yeah!)
I'll believe in the day it reaches someone's heart. (Yeah!)
何千回...何万回 冷たい雨が降っても
Even if cold rain falls thousands... tens of thousands of times,
歌声にのせてモノクロの世界を
I'll take my singing voice and color this monochrome world
鮮やかに彩るよ
vibrantly.
私の色で
With my own color.
Music & Lyric 40mP / Guitar [TEST]
Movie, Illust & Mix 風真いろは
Music & Lyric: 40mP / Guitar: [TEST]
Movie, Illust & Mix: Kazama Iroha
はい！というわけで、覚えていましたか？皆殿。
Yes! And so, did you remember it, everyone?
40mPさんの「Color of Drops」。
40mP-san's "Color of Drops."
デビュー配信の時にパソコン壊しちゃって、お披露目できなかった曲を
I broke my PC during my debut stream, so I couldn't showcase this song back then.
1周年でダンス付きでお届けさせていただきました！
But now, for my 1st anniversary, I performed it with a dance!
やったー！届いたー！
Hooray! It reached you!
皆殿、パソコン直ってよかったでござる。壊しちゃったけど、
Everyone, I'm so glad the PC is fixed. It broke, but...
皆殿のパワー注入のおかげで直りまして...ありがとうございます。
...thanks to everyone injecting their power, it's fixed! Thank you.
そして、じゃん！見てください！
And, ta-da! Look at this!
風真のアイドル衣装、このようになっております！
Kazama's idol outfit looks like this!
どうですか？想像してたのと皆殿、合ってた？
What do you think? Did it match what you imagined, everyone?
どう？どうどうどう？
Well? How is it? How is it?
後ろもね、結構あの、風真のイメージカラーをいっぱいね、入れていただいて。
The back also has a lot of Kazama's image colors incorporated.
足元とかもこの、通常衣装の靴下の対になっております！
Even the feet are a pair with the socks from my usual outfit!
え、どうでござるか？可愛い？本当に？可愛いしかない？
Well, how is it? Is it cute? Really? Only cute?
そう、このタイプかってコメントあったら、そう、風真は、このタイプになりました！
If people comment "Oh, it's this type," yes, Kazama became this type!
そして、気づきました？「Color of Drops」始まる前に、
And, did you notice? Before "Color of Drops" started,
なんかパソコンが直ったから、ここ！
since the PC got fixed, look here!
じゃん！オリジナルのマイクを、手に入れました！
Ta-da! I got an original microphone!
やったー！本当にね、これもね、すごい1周年配信までに準備していたものなんですけど、
Hooray! Actually, this was also something I prepared very hard for the 1st anniversary stream,
パソコン壊して一時はどうなるかと思いました。
but when the PC broke, I wondered what would happen for a moment.
でも無事にね、皆殿のおかげで直りました。ありがとうございます。
But safely, thanks to everyone, it's fixed. Thank you.
そしてもう一つ！もうお気づきかもしれませんが、ステージ、冬になりました！
And one more thing! You might have noticed already, but the stage has turned into winter!
さむっ！風真は寒いところから来た侍だからまだ耐えられるけど、
Cold! Kazama is a samurai from a cold place, so I can still bear it,
これは風真じゃなかったら耐えられなかったでござるな。寒い！
but if it wasn't Kazama, they wouldn't have been able to stand it. So cold!
寒いけど、どう？雪景色綺麗でござるでしょ？
It's cold, but how is it? The snowy landscape is beautiful, right?
冬になりました。春からスタートして、冬までここまでやってきました。
It's winter. Starting from spring, we've come all the way to winter.
風真のね、デビューの軌跡をね、同じようになぞらせていただきましたが、
I've traced the trajectory of my debut in the same way,
やっぱり風真も1周年、もちろん出ます！あれが！そう、グッズです！
but of course, for the 1st anniversary, it's coming out! That thing! Yes, merch!
お待たせいたしました！それでは詳細は、こちら！
Thank you for waiting! Now, for the details, look here!
はい！風真いろは、活動1周年記念のグッズ、11月30日販売開始でござる！
Yes! Kazama Iroha 1st Anniversary Commemorative Merch, on sale November 30th!
見て！めっちゃ可愛い！もう、もう色々天才すぎてね、
Look! It's so cute! Everything is just too genius,
ちょっと尺足りるかなって思うんでござるが、説明させていただきますので、
I wonder if I'll have enough time, but I'll explain them,
じゃあ順番にいきましょう！じゃあまずは、ラバーマットから！
so let's go in order! Okay, first, starting with the rubber mat!
はい、こちらでござる！今回はね、またやってもらいました！
Yes, here it is! This time, I had them do it again!
うみぼうずママ殿に書いていただきました！
Umibouzu-mama-dono illustrated it!
このステージでね、いっぱい踊ってる風真を撮ってもらいました！
She captured Kazama dancing a lot on this stage!
ママ殿、ありがとー！ありがとうございます！
Mama-dono, thank you! Thank you so much!
ね、ぜひいっぱい使ってほしいです！そして2つ目！
I really want everyone to use it a lot! And the second one!
はい、3連結アクリルキーホルダー！こちらのイラストは、
Yes, a 3-link acrylic keychain! The illustration for this is by...
風真のメンバーシップスタンプなどをご担当いただいております、
Suzumishiro-sensei, who handles Kazama's membership stamps and such!
すずみしろ先生にご担当いただきました！ありがとうございます！
She was in charge of this one! Thank you so much!
なかったようで、今まで...あったようでなかった、
It seemed like it didn't exist... it seemed like it did but it didn't,
チャキ丸のキーホルダーがね、追加されておりまして、
but a Chakimaru keychain has been added,
風真とぽこべぇとチャキ丸、3種繋がるキーホルダーになっております！
making it a 3-link keychain with Kazama, Pokobee, and Chakimaru!
鞄に付けて　ブラ下げて連れてってね。
Attach them to your bag and take them along with you.
そして次！　これも頑張りました。
And next! I worked hard on this one too.
こちら！　今回　風真がデザインさせていただきました...
This! This time, Kazama got to design it herself...
...ぽこべえスマホリングでござる！
...it's the Pokobee smartphone ring!
可愛いでしょ？　ちょっと頑張ってデザインしてみました。
Cute, right? I put a lot of effort into the design.
なんかデビューの最初からね　ぽこべえのお尻は...
Ever since my debut, I've wanted to make something...
...何かグッズで作りたいなと思っていたので...
...using Pokobee's bottom as a piece of merch...
...今回はスマホリングにしてみました。
...so this time, I turned it into a smartphone ring.
皆殿の毎日使ってるスマホに　ぜひくっつけて...
I'd be happy if you all attached it to the phones you use every day...
...ぽこべえ　一緒に連れてってくれると嬉しいなって思います。
...and took Pokobee along with you.
そして！　もうこれ　超待望！　皆殿待ってたでしょ？　これです！
And! This is much-awaited! You've all been waiting for this, right? Here it is!
ぽこべえの　ぬいぐるみでーす！
It's the Pokobee plushie!
やっと皆殿のお家にも　ぽこべえがお迎えできるようになりました。
Finally, Pokobee can find a home with all of you.
もうね　皆が「ぽこべえ欲しい！　うちにも来てくれ！」って言ってたので...
Since everyone was saying, 'I want Pokobee! Come to my house!'...
...ぽこべえね　ここ数日間　留守にしていたんですが...
...Pokobee has been away for the last few days...
...出張して　ぬいぐるみのサンプルになってまいりました！
...traveling to become a sample for this plushie!
どうだ！　可愛いだろ？　ぽこべえ！　え　可愛い？
How is it? Isn't Pokobee cute? Isn't he?
巾着ぽこべえって言うな！　おい　巾着ぽこべえって言うな！　やめろ！
Don't call him 'Drawstring Pokobee'! Hey, don't say 'Drawstring Pokobee'! Stop it!
でーも　でも　でも！　可愛いでしょ？　可愛いでしょ？
But, but, but! He's cute, isn't he? Isn't he?
風真もね　ちょっと大量に購入して...
I'm going to buy a bunch of them too...
...あの　枕の周りに　いっぱい置こうと思います。
...and put them all around my pillow.
ろしくお願いします！　スタッフさんにも大人気です！　ありがとうございます。
Please check it out! It's very popular with the staff too! Thank you.
そしてそして　フルセットがこのように　なっております。　どどん！
And the full set looks like this. Ta-da!
ね　ありがとうございます。　そして　フルセットをご購入いただきますと...
Yes, thank you. And if you purchase the full set...
風真いろは　箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入り...
you get a postcard featuring an illustration by Umibouzu-sensei...
...うみぼうず先生描き下ろしポストカードが付いてくるのと...
...with my foil-stamped signature and message!
今回　頑張りました。　特典ボイスです！　特典ボイス頑張って撮ったよ！
I also worked hard on this. It's a special bonus voice! I worked hard on it!
ライブ前後のね　楽屋でのね　シチュエーションボイスとなっております。
It's a situation voice set in the dressing room before and after the live.
頑張って撮りましたので　恥ずかしいんですけど...
I worked hard on it, so I'm a bit embarrassed...
...ちょっと緊張している風真　そして　ライブが終わって...
...but I hope you enjoy the time with a nervous Kazama...
...「頑張ったなー」ってなってる風真との　ひとときを一緒に過ごしてもらえたら。
...and the Kazama who's like, 'I did my best!' after the show.
嬉しいなと思います。　よろしくお願いします！
I'd be very happy. Thank you!
はい　この後　21時から販売開始であってるかな？
Yes, sales start from 9 PM today, right?
だと思いますので　ぜひぜひチェックしてください！　お願いします！
I think so, so please check it out! Please!
デザインとか色々頑張ったから　皆殿の手に届くと嬉しいです。
I worked hard on the designs and everything, so I hope it reaches you all.
そして　メンバーシップのね　この後　配信があります！
And next, we have a membership-exclusive stream!
21時15分からメン限配信がありますので。
The stream starts at 9:15 PM.
アフターアフタートーク？　そしてね　ライブもあり　写真撮影もあり...
An after-after talk? Plus another live performance, a photo session...
...なんでもあり！　そして　まだまだここで出していない...
...and even more! I've also got many more...
...新要素のお披露目がたくさんありますので...
...unrevealed things to show you all...
...メンバーシップの方は　ぜひ遊びに来てください。
...so membership holders, please come and join!
そして　21時からは　メンバーシップ限定の壁紙も公開されます！
Also, from 9 PM, the membership-exclusive wallpaper will be released!
今回ね　サムネご担当いただきました　ぱるまろ先生に...
This time, Palmaro-sensei, who did the thumbnail...
...メンバーシップ限定用のサブも描いていただいておりますので。
...also drew a sub-illustration specifically for membership holders.
絶対にね　お見逃しなく　チェックしてください！
Make sure you don't miss it and check it out!
はい...　いっぱい喋ったな...　いっぱい喋ったね。
Whew... I've talked a lot... I really did talk a lot.
ここまでね　1年　色々ありました。
It's been a year full of various experiences.
正直ね　パソコン壊しちゃって　今日どうしようってなってたでござるが...
To be honest, my PC broke and I was worried about what to do today...
...無事にまず配信できてよかったです。
...but I'm just glad I could stream safely.
今日　風真からね　皆殿にね　いっぱい「ありがとう」はあるんですが...
I have so many 'thank yous' to give to all of you today...
...他にも「ありがとう」をいっぱい伝えたい人がいます。
...but there are other people I want to thank as well.
まず　このライブのね　先輩方！　ここまでね　支えてくださり...
First, my seniors in this live! Thank you so much...
...本当にありがとうございました。
for supporting me up until now!
そしてね　運営スタッフさんも　ここまでね...
And the management staff as well...
...本当　ライブの準備とか大変だからね　一生懸命動いてくださって...
preparing for a live is a lot of work, and you all worked so hard...
...本当にありがとうございましたでござる。
so thank you very much!
そして　HoloXのみんな！　見てるか？　見てるでござるか？
And my HoloX members! Are you watching? Are you guys watching?
ずっとね　5人で　色々悩んだり　励まし合ったり　ここまで来れて。
The five of us have always worried together and encouraged each other to get here.
そして　1年をね　5人で迎えられて　本当に本当に嬉しいです。
And I'm truly, truly happy that all five of us could celebrate our first anniversary.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much!
頼りない用心棒ですが　これからもジャキンジャキンしていくので...
I may be an unreliable bodyguard, but I'll keep on 'shakin-shakin'...
...よろしくお願いします！　ありがとう　HoloXのみんな！　大好きでござる。
so please keep supporting me! Thank you, HoloX! I love you guys!
そして　皆殿！　今日も配信見てくれて　ありがとうございました。
And to all of you! Thank you for watching the stream today.
ちょっとね　至らないとこばかりの隊長ですが...
I'm a commander with many shortcomings...
...この2年目も　強くなったとこね　いっぱい見せていきたいと思いますので。
but in this second year, I want to show you how much stronger I've become.
目をそらさず...　そらさず！　そらさないで！　目を離さず...
Without looking away... Don't look away! Please don't look away!
...しっかりついてきてください！
Keep your eyes on me and follow me closely!
風真も　この2年目は　もっともっともっと頑張ります！
In my second year, I will work even, even, even harder!
ろしくお願いします！
Thank you for your support!
よし！　言いたいこと全部言った！　全部言ったね。
Alright! I've said everything I wanted to say! I really have.
皆殿ありがとう！　これからもよろしくお願いします。
Thank you all! I look forward to your continued support.
それでは　ずっと待っていただいただろう　この発表をさせていただきます。
And now, I'd like to make the announcement you've all been waiting for.
お待たせしました！
Thank you for waiting!
待望の風真いろは　オリジナルソングが　発売決定しました！
Kazama Iroha's long-awaited original song is finally set for release!
やったー！　あ　もう出てる！　早い！
Yay! Oh, it's already out! That was fast!
ありがとうございます。　この後　24時から販売開始でござる！
Thank you. Sales will begin today from midnight!
ございますので 是非是非チェックしてください
So please be sure to check it out.
曲名は いろはすてっぷ！
The title is "Iroha Step!"
はい 曲は 40mPさんに作っていただきまして
Yes, the song was created by 40mP-san.
えっと こちらのジャケットイラストは つむぎ先生
And the jacket illustration is by Tsumugi-sensei,
ロゴは ひらぎりょう先生にご担当いただきました
and the logo was designed by Hiragi Ryo-sensei.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
たくさんたくさん 元気が出る曲なんで
It's a song that gives you a lot of energy,
たくさんたくさん 皆様に聴いてもらえると嬉しいです
so I'd be happy if everyone listens to it a lot.
よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
やばい ちょっと待って 泣いちゃう前にね もう泣いちゃう前に
Oh no, wait, before I start crying... before I cry,
この熱がね 冷めないうちに
while this excitement is still hot...
この今発表した オリ曲を 歌って踊ります！
I'm going to sing and dance to the original song I just announced!
それでは 聴いてください
Now, please listen.
風真いろは オリジナルソング いろはすてっぷ！
Kazama Iroha's original song, "Iroha Step!"
風がそっと吹いたら
When the wind blows softly
始まる合図で
With the signal to start
ござる！
Gozaru!
いろはすてっぷ！ 作詞・作曲: 40mP
Iroha Step! Lyrics/Composition: 40mP
Ah このハードモードな日々
Ah, these hard-mode days
Days 歩き出すことためらうけど
Days, though I hesitate to start walking
BGM決めて さあ 人生エンジョイ勢で
Pick your BGM, come on, let's enjoy life
のんびり行こう
Let's go at our own pace
先の見えない乱世
In this unpredictable world of chaos
自分の道辿りゃんせ
Please follow your own path
オーケー 生きてりゃきっと 何とかなるさ
OK, as long as you're alive, things will work out somehow
だいじょぶ だいじょぶ！
It's okay, it's okay!
後ろ？ 前？ 方向なんてわからない
Back? Front? I don't even know which direction is which
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
Even in these days like a lost maze
一歩 歩き出せたら
If you can take one step forward
それが前になるのさ
That becomes "forward"
万事快調気分な朝でも
Whether it's a morning where everything's going great
頭渋滞気味な夜でも
Or a night where your mind feels congested
風がいつも吹いてる
The wind is always blowing
心配しないで
Don't worry
一緒にファイトで
Let's fight together
ござる！
Gozaru!
Ah まだ履き慣れていない シューズ
Ah, these shoes I'm still not used to wearing,
転びそうにばっかになって
keep making me almost trip
七転び八起き 何回でもゲームオーバー
Falling seven times, getting up eight, no matter how many game overs
コンティニューしよう
Let's continue
地獄の沙汰も自分次第
Even the judgments of hell depend on you
たまにミスって非常事態
Sometimes messing up and causing an emergency
シーザス 生きてりゃそういう 時だってあるさ
Jesus, as long as you're alive, there are times like that
だいじょぶ だいじょぶ！
It's okay, it's okay!
右 左 1, 2, 3が聞こえない
Right, left, I can't hear the 1, 2, 3
よもや突発的な運命も
Even an unexpected fate
グッドタイミングな予感
Feels like a premonition of good timing
思い立ったが吉日さ
There's no time like the present
いつも現実主義なあの人も
Even that person who's always a realist
かたや空想癖な誰かも
Or someone else with a daydreaming habit
夢の中で会えたら
If we can meet in a dream
遊び明かしましょう
Let's play all night long
それじゃあね おやすみ
Well then, goodnight
色は匂へど 散りぬるを
Though the colors are fragrant, they will scatter
終わりなき 始まりは
An endless beginning
歌いながら 風のままに
Singing along with the wind
ゆけ！
Go!
後ろ？ 前？ 方向なんてわからない
Back? Front? I don't even know which direction is which
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
Even in these days like a lost maze
一歩 歩き出せたら
If you can take one step forward
それが前になるのさ
That becomes "forward"
万事快調気分な朝でも
Whether it's a morning where everything's going great
頭渋滞気味な夜でも
Or a night where your mind feels congested
風がいつも吹いてる
The wind is always blowing
心配しないで
Don't worry
自分のペースで
At your own pace
一緒にファイトで
Let's fight together
ござる！
Gozaru!
というわけで 風真いろは1周年LIVE 最後まで見ていただき
And so, thank you for watching Kazama Iroha's 1st Anniversary LIVE
ありがとうございました！
until the very end!
2年目も 頑張っていくので
I'll keep doing my best in my second year too,
よろしくお願いします 皆様本当にありがとう！
so please continue to support me. Thank you so much, everyone!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!